{
    "question": "738)\uf020 Government launched mobile app \u201cJanaushadhi\nSugam\u201d for what purpose",
    "answer": " Toenablepeople to\nsearch Janaushadhi generic medicines stores\n"
}{
    "question": "739)\uf020 As per the Forbes list of highest paid women in\nmusic, who has been ranked no. 1 in world",
    "answer": "\nTaylor Swift, USA\n"
}{
    "question": "740)\uf020 Name the Hollywood star who topped the Forbes\u2019\nlist of highest-paid female actors in the world",
    "answer": "\nScarlett Johansson\n"
}{
    "question": "741)\uf020 Bandhan Bank launched a co-branded credit card\nin association with",
    "answer": " Standard Chartered Bank\n"
}{
    "question": "742)\uf020 What is the name of the National Sports Awards\ngiven for excellence in adventure sports",
    "answer": " Tenzing\nNorgay National Adventure Award\n"
}{
    "question": "743)\uf020 Name any two adventure sports categories for\nwhich national sports award is given",
    "answer": " Water\nadventure, Air Adventure\n"
}{
    "question": "744)\uf020 The RBI decided to transfer 1.76 lakh crore\nrupees as dividend and surplus reserve to the\ngovernment. The decision is based on\nrecommendations of which committee",
    "answer": " Bimal\nJalan Committee\n"
}{
    "question": "745)\uf020 Dense rain forest of which region are often\nreferred to as \"Lungs of the Earth\"",
    "answer": " Amazon\nForests in Brazil\n"
}{
    "question": "746)\uf020 Why Amazon forests are referred to as \"Lungs of\nthe Earth\"",
    "answer": " They contribute over 20 per cent of\nworld 's oxygen content\n"
}{
    "question": "747)\uf020 The Amazon forests were in news recently for\nwhat reasons",
    "answer": " They were stuck by hundreds of\nwildfires causing wide spread devastation of\ngreen cover\n"
}{
    "question": "748)\uf020 The Delhi and District Cricket Association, DDCA\nhas decided to rename the Feroz Shah Kotla\nStadium as what",
    "answer": " ArunJaitely Stadium\n"
}{
    "question": "749)\uf020 Abdalla Hamdok, a prominent economist has been\nsworn in as Prime Minister of which African\ncountry",
    "answer": " Sudan\n"
}{
    "question": "750)\uf020 Which apex national organization released the\nComposite Water Management Index 2.0 for\n2017-18",
    "answer": " NITI Aayog\n"
}{
    "question": "751)\uf020 Which state has been ranked as No. 1 in the\nComposite Water Management Index 2.0",
    "answer": " Gujarat\n"
}{
    "question": "752)\uf020 Which International Day is observed on August\n21 to raise awareness about the condition of older\npeople",
    "answer": " World Senior Citizens Day\n"
}{
    "question": "753)\uf020 On August 26, which international day is\ncelebrated across the world to promote gender\nequality",
    "answer": " Women's Equality Day\n"
}{
    "question": "754)\uf020 What is the name of the oldest Football\nTournament of Asia, finals of which was played in\nKolkata",
    "answer": " Durand Cup\n"
}{
    "question": "755)\uf020 Komalika Bari became the recurve cadet world\nchampion in which sports",
    "answer": " Archery\n"
}{
    "question": "756)\uf020 P V Sindhu scripted history as she became the\nfirst Indian to win badminton\u2019s World\nChampionships. She defeated which player",
    "answer": "\nNozomi Okuhara of Japan\n"
}{
    "question": "757)\uf020 Who won the Men's singles title of the BWFWorld Badminton Championship at Basel,\nSwitzerland",
    "answer": " KentoMomota of Japan\n"
}{
    "question": "758)\uf020 Which Indian player won the Bronze in men\u2019s\nsingles at the World Badminton Championships",
    "answer": "\nB Sai Praneeth\n"
}{
    "question": "759)\uf020 The Indian Army has entered into an arrangement\nwith which real estate firm to take over dwelling\nunits in 13 \u2018Ready to Move in\u2019 pan-India projects",
    "answer": "\nTata Realty & Housing\n"
}{
    "question": "760)\uf020 The Financial Action Task Force\u2019s Asia Pacific\nGroup recently blacklisted which country for noncompliance and non-enforcement of safeguards\nagainst terror financing and money laundering",
    "answer": "\nPakistan\n"
}{
    "question": "761)\uf020 Where are the headquarters of the Financial\nAction Task Force",
    "answer": " Paris\n"
}{
    "question": "762)\uf020 Which apex Indian organization has announced a \nGYANM GENERAL AWARENESS \u2013FEBRUARY 2020 99\nnew mechanism to reward insider trading\ninformants to uncover insider trading cases",
    "answer": " SEBI\n- Securities and Exchange Board of India\n"
}{
    "question": "763)\uf020 Which country launched an unmanned rocket\ncarrying a life-size humanoid robot named Fedor",
    "answer": "\nRussia\n"
}{
    "question": "764)\uf020 The humanoid robot Fedor will function at which\nplace",
    "answer": " International Space Station\n"
}{
    "question": "765)\uf020 Which two Indian places have been featured in\nthe Time\u2019s list of the 100 greatest places in the\nworld",
    "answer": " 'Statue of Unity' in Gujarat and 'Soho\nHouse' in Mumbai\n"
}{
    "question": "766)\uf020 Which state topped the SARAL Index, which\nevaluates the Indian states on the basis of their\nattractiveness for rooftop solar development",
    "answer": "\nKarnataka\n"
}{
    "question": "767)\uf020 What is the expansion of the acronym SARAL",
    "answer": "\nState Rooftop Solar Attractiveness\n"
}{
    "question": "768)\uf020 As per Forbes' list of highest-paid actors, which\nBollywood star secured the fourth position with\nearnings of $65 million (about Rs 450 crore)",
    "answer": "\nAkshay Kumar\n"
}{
    "question": "769)\uf020 Indian Railways started its second double-decker\ntrain \u201cUday Express\u201d. It will run between which\ntwo stations",
    "answer": " Visakhapatnam and Vijayawada\nin Andhra Pradesh\n"
}{
    "question": "770)\uf020 What is the full form of UDAY",
    "answer": " Utkrisht Doubledecker Air conditioned Yatri\n"
}{
    "question": "771)\uf020 RBI has permitted processing of e-mandate on\ncredit and debit cards and e-wallets for recurring\ntransactions (merchant payments) with a cap of\nRs _______ per transaction",
    "answer": " 2,000\n"
}{
    "question": "772)\uf020 The RBI has ruled that registration and first\ntransaction of e-mandate will require AFA. What\nis AFA",
    "answer": " Additional Factor of Authentication\n"
}{
    "question": "773)\uf020 The centre has notified new sets of health\nwarnings for all tobacco products. What it is",
    "answer": "\nTobacco causes painful death\n"
}{
    "question": "774)\uf020 Ministry of Railways has directed all its units to\nenforce ban on which type of plastic material\nfrom October 2 this year",
    "answer": " Single use plastics\n"
}{
    "question": "775)\uf020 Give some common examples of single use plastic\nitems",
    "answer": " Disposable items, glasses, bottles, etc.\n"
}{
    "question": "776)\uf020 Which country conferred her highest civilian\nhonour 'Order of Zayed' on Sh. Modi",
    "answer": " UAE- United\nArab Emirates\n"
}{
    "question": "777)\uf020 King of which country honoured our Prime\nMinister with \"The King Hamad Order of the\nRenaissance\"",
    "answer": " Bahrain\n"
}{
    "question": "778)\uf020 The 45th G7 summit was held in _________, France",
    "answer": "\nBiarritz\n"
}{
    "question": "779)\uf020 Which e-commerce major inaugurated its largest\ncampus in the world, in Hyderabad",
    "answer": " Amazon\n"
}{
    "question": "780)\uf020 The National Sports Awards 2019were\nannounced by Selection Committee headed by\nretired judge Justice _______",
    "answer": " Mukundakam\nSharma\n"
}{
    "question": "781)\uf020 Which is the highest recognition from the Govt. of\nIndia for outstanding achievements in sports",
    "answer": "\nRajiv Gandhi Khel Ratna\n"
}{
    "question": "782)\uf020 How many sports person were selected in 2019\nfor the Rajiv Gandhi Khel Ratna Award",
    "answer": " Two\n"
}{
    "question": "783)\uf020 Name the star wrestler who won the Rajiv Gandhi\nKhel Ratna Award 2019",
    "answer": " Bajrang Punia\n"
}{
    "question": "784)\uf020 Paralympian Deepa Malik has been selected for\nRajiv Gandhi Khel Ratna Award for outstanding\nachievements in which sports",
    "answer": " Athletics - Shotput\n"
}{
    "question": "785)\uf020 The Govt. of India honours veteran sports coaches\nwith which award",
    "answer": " Dronacharya Award\n"
}{
    "question": "786)\uf020 Which national sports award is given to honour\nthe veteran sports persons for their life time\nachievement",
    "answer": " Dhyan Chand Award\n"
}{
    "question": "787)\uf020 India celebrates National Sports Day on which\ndate",
    "answer": " August 29 (birthday- Sh. Dhyan Chand)\n"
}{
    "question": "788)\uf020 According to an analysis of a NASA data released\nby environmental watchdog NGO Greenpeace,\n_________ is the world's largest emitter of\nanthropogenic Sulphur Dioxide",
    "answer": " India\n"
}{
    "question": "789)\uf020 What is the main source that releases Sulphur\nDioxide in the atmosphere",
    "answer": " Coal burning\n"
}{
    "question": "790)\uf020 The HRD ministry launched the Integrated\nTeachers Training Programme,NISHTHA",
    "answer": "To\nbuild and improve the capacities of around 42\nlakh teachers across India\n"
}{
    "question": "791)\uf020 What is the full form of acronym NISHTHA",
    "answer": "\nNational Initiative for School Head\u2019s and\nTeachers\u2019 Holistic Advancement\n"
}{
    "question": "792)\uf020 The Task Force headed by Akhilesh Ranjan for\nreview of Income Tax Act and drafting of new DTC\nsubmitted its report. What is DTC",
    "answer": " Direct Tax\nCode\n"
}{
    "question": "793)\uf020 Biographical documentary \u201c100 Years of\nChrysostom\u201d was in news recently for what\nreasons",
    "answer": " It was selected for the Guinness\nAward in the category of longest documentary,\nrunning for 48 hrs and 8 minutes\n"
}{
    "question": "794)\uf020 Biographical documentary \u201c100 Years of\nChrysostom\u201d is related to life of which great saint",
    "answer": "\nPhilipose Mar Chrysostom, Kerala\n"
}{
    "question": "795)\uf020 World Humanitarian Day is observed across the\nworld with UN support on which date to pay\ntribute to workers who risk their lives in\nhumanitarian services",
    "answer": " August 19\n"
}{
    "question": "796)\uf020 ________ defeated China to win the gold medal at\nthe Under 12 Asian Tennis Team championship\nheld in Kazakhstan",
    "answer": " India\n"
}{
    "question": "797)\uf020 A one of its kind underground Bunker Museum\nhas been opened at Raj Bhavan of which state",
    "answer": "\nMaharashtra (Mumbai)\n"
}{
    "question": "798)\uf020 The Prime Minister in his Independence Day\nspeech announced the launch of \u201cJal Jeevan \nGYANM GENERAL AWARENESS \u2013FEBRUARY 2020 100\nMission\u201d for what purpose",
    "answer": " To provide piped\nwater supply to every house by 2024\n"
}{
    "question": "799)\uf020 Justice Madan B Lokur, retired Supreme Court\njudge has been appointed a judge on the\nnonresident panel of the Supreme Court of which\ncountry",
    "answer": " Fiji\n"
}{
    "question": "800)\uf020 Who has been re-appointed as the head coach of\nthe Indian men\u2019s cricket team by the Cricket\nAdvisory Committee of BCCI",
    "answer": " Ravi Shastri\n"
}{
    "question": "801)\uf020 On August 15, ________ became the first Indian\nairline to fly over the North Pole connecting New\nDelhi to San Francisco",
    "answer": " Air India\n"
}{
    "question": "802)\uf020 RBI has asked banks that transactions failed due\nto technical reasons at ATMs or due to nonavailability of cash, should not be _________",
    "answer": "\nIncluded in the \"free ATM transactions\"\npermitted every month\n"
}{
    "question": "803)\uf020 Prime Minister in his Independence Day speech\nannounced that the country will now have a CDS.\nWhat is CDS",
    "answer": " Chief of Defence Staff\n"
}{
    "question": "804)\uf020 The \u2018abhishekamprasadamPanchamirtham\u2019of\nMurugan temple, Palani has been granted GI-Tag.\nIt is in which state",
    "answer": " Tamil Nadu\n"
}{
    "question": "805)\uf020 Priyam Chatterjeebecame the 1st Indian to be\nawarded the 'Chevalier de l\u2019Ordre du M\u00e9rite\nAgricole' by the government of France for\nachievement in which field",
    "answer": " Cookery\n"
}{
    "question": "806)\uf020 Which state won the \u201cbest innovation and\ninitiative leadership award\u201d in the World\nEducation Summit-2019 held in New Delhi",
    "answer": "\nRajasthan\n"
}{
    "question": "807)\uf020 Railway Protection Force (RPF) launched a\nspecial drive code named \"Operation Number\nPlate\u201d for what purpose",
    "answer": " To identify and verify\nall vehicles parked in Railway premises\n"
}{
    "question": "808)\uf020 _________ became the first ever batsman in the\nworld to score 20,000 international runs in a\nsingle decade",
    "answer": " Virat Kohli\n"
}{
    "question": "809)\uf020 International Youth Day is observed on which\ndate",
    "answer": " August 12\n"
}{
    "question": "810)\uf020 The 2022 Commonwealth Games will be held at\nwhich place",
    "answer": " Birmingham, UK\n"
}{
    "question": "811)\uf020 International Cricket Council and Commonwealth\nGames Federation have confirmed the inclusion of\nwhich cricket event in 2022 Birmingham\nCommonwealth Games",
    "answer": " Women's T-20\n"
}{
    "question": "812)\uf020 Central government has made \"Headgear\"\n(wearing a helmet) mandatory for children above\n_____ years while travelling on a\nmotorcycle/scooter in public place",
    "answer": " Four\n"
}{
    "question": "813)\uf020 In one of India\u2019s largest ever foreign direct\ninvestment deals to date, which company\ninvested $75 billion in Reliance Petro",
    "answer": " Saudi\nAramco\n"
}{
    "question": "814)\uf020 On August 09, which day is observed around the\nworld to promote interest of indigenous people\nand tribals",
    "answer": " World Tribal Day\n"
}{
    "question": "815)\uf020 \u2018Samagra Shiksha-Jal Suraksha\u2019 mission has been\nlaunched by the _____ ministry to create\nawareness about Water Conservation among all\nschool students in the country",
    "answer": " HRD\n"
}{
    "question": "816)\uf020 Which Sikh museum in Punjab became the most\nvisited museum in the Indian subcontinent",
    "answer": "\nVirasat-e-Khalsa Museum, Anandpur Sahib\n"
}{
    "question": "817)\uf020 The 66th National Film Awards were announced\non August 9 by the jury headed by veteran film\ndirector _______",
    "answer": " Rahul Rawail\n"
}{
    "question": "818)\uf020 The national award for most film friendly state\nwas given to which state",
    "answer": " Uttarakhand\n"
}{
    "question": "819)\uf020 Which film won the national award for best\nfeature film",
    "answer": " Hellaro(Gujarati)\n"
}{
    "question": "820)\uf020 Hindi film \"Badhaai Ho\" won which top national\nfilm award",
    "answer": " Best Popular Film\n"
}{
    "question": "821)\uf020 Which film won the National award for the best\nHindi film",
    "answer": " Andhadhun\n"
}{
    "question": "822)\uf020 Which global card company launched a nextgeneration, mobile-first authentication solution,\n\u201cIdentity Check Express\u201d",
    "answer": " MasterCard\n"
}{
    "question": "823)\uf020 Which Indian transsexual woman won the crown\nof Miss World Diversity 2019 at a pageant held in\nPort Louis",
    "answer": " Naaz Joshi\n"
}{
    "question": "824)\uf020 Which world day is observed on August 06 to\nfocus on creating awareness for anti-war and\nanti-nuclear discussions and demonstrations",
    "answer": "\nHiroshima Day\n"
}{
    "question": "825)\uf020 National Handloom Day is observed on which\ndate",
    "answer": " August 07\n"
}{
    "question": "826)\uf020 Which apex body plans to set up a central\npayment fraud registry, which will monitor digital\npayment frauds on real-time basis",
    "answer": " Reserve\nBank of India\n"
}{
    "question": "827)\uf020 The RBI has decided to allow round-the-clock\nfund transfers through which channel from\nDecember this year in order to promote digital\ntransactions",
    "answer": " National Electronic Funds\nTransfer (NEFT)\n"
}{
    "question": "828)\uf020 The day on which Mahatma Gandhi gave a clarion\ncall to end the British rule and launched the Quit\nIndia Movement in 1942 is celebrated as which\nday on August 8",
    "answer": " August Kranti Diwas\n"
}{
    "question": "829)\uf020 Tamil Nadu\u2019s Pathamadai mats have been granted\nGeographical Indication (GI) tag. These mats are\nused at",
    "answer": " Wedding ceremonies\n"
}{
    "question": "830)\uf020 Who is the only athlete from the country to find a\nplace in the Highest-Paid Female Athletes 2019\nlist released by Forbes of USA",
    "answer": " P V Sindhu, 13th\n"
}{
    "question": "831)\uf020 Marble from Makrana in Rajasthan is now Asia\u2019s\nfirst Global Heritage Stone Resource. Name any\nfamous Indian monument made with this marble",
    "answer": "\nTaj Mahal\n"
}{
    "question": "832)\uf020 SatwiksairajRankireddy and Chirag Shetty\ncreated history by becoming the first Indian pair \nGYANM GENERAL AWARENESS \u2013FEBRUARY 2020 101\nto win a ______ badminton tournament",
    "answer": " BWF\nSuper 500\n"
}{
    "question": "833)\uf020 Government has set up a joint venture company\n'KABIL' for what purpose",
    "answer": " To ensure supply of\n12 critical minerals to Indian domestic market\n"
}{
    "question": "834)\uf020 What is the full expansion of the acronym 'KABIL'",
    "answer": "\nKhanijBidesh India Limited\n"
}{
    "question": "835)\uf020 Which Arabian country passed new laws to\nremove age old restrictions on independent\nmovement of women",
    "answer": " Saudi Arabia\n"
}{
    "question": "836)\uf020 What is the single most important feature of the\nUnlawful Activities (Prevention) Amendment\n(UAPA) Bill, 2019 recently passed by the\nParliament",
    "answer": " Powerto designate a person as a\nterrorist\n"
}{
    "question": "837)\uf020 In a recent report released by the World Bank on\nthe global GDP rankings 2018, India has slipped\nto the ____ place from fifth place last year",
    "answer": " 7th\n"
}{
    "question": "838)\uf020 What is the formal name of the recently passed\nthe Triple Talaq Bill",
    "answer": " Muslim Women\n(Protection of Rights on Marriage) Bill, 2019\n"
}{
    "question": "839)\uf020 As per the Triple Talaq Bill, the practice of instant\ntriple talaq is punishable by a jail term of how\nmany years",
    "answer": " Three\n"
}{
    "question": "840)\uf020 Which cricketer crossed a rare mile stone of\nscoring 1000 runs and taking 100 wickets in the\nT20 format",
    "answer": " Ms.Ellyse Perry, Australia\n"
}{
    "question": "841)\uf020 Name the senior Indian TV journalist who was\none of the five persons selected for the\nprestigious Ramon Magsaysay award",
    "answer": " Ravish\nKumar\n"
}{
    "question": "842)\uf020 Ravish Kumar is popular for anchoring which\nHindi TV news programme",
    "answer": " Prime Time on\nNDTV\n"
}{
    "question": "843)\uf020 Which legendary Football club celebrated its 100\nyears of existence on August 01 in Kolkata",
    "answer": " East\nBengal Club\n"
}{
    "question": "844)\uf020 Which country passed a law to ban burqa or\nniqab, in public buildings and on transport",
    "answer": "\nNetherlands\n"
}{
    "question": "845)\uf020 India signed a deal worth around Rs 1,500 crore\nto acquire which air-to-air hypersonic missiles\nfrom Russia",
    "answer": " R-27\n"
}{
    "question": "846)\uf020 Indian Navyrecently inducted indigenously built\nINS LCU L-56. It is which type of ship",
    "answer": " Landing\nCraft Utility (LCU) MK IV class ships\n"
}{
    "question": "847)\uf020 VidishaBaliyan, young beauty queen from Uttar\nPradesh won which international beauty crown\nrecently",
    "answer": " Miss Deaf World 2019\n"
}{
    "question": "848)\uf020 Jerlin Anika,15 year Tamil Nadu girl won the gold\nmedal in the World Deaf Youth _______\nChampionships held in Taipei",
    "answer": " Badminton\n"
}{
    "question": "849)\uf020 UNO supports celebration of July 30 as a special\nday devoted to raise awareness about the\nsituation of victims of human trafficking. Name\nthis day",
    "answer": " World Day Against Trafficking\n"
}{
    "question": "850)\uf020 After giving GI-Tag to west Bengal for Rasagola in\nNov. 2017, which other state has now been given\nGI-Tag for Rasagola",
    "answer": " Odisha\n"
}{
    "question": "851)\uf020 Which house of Parliament - Lok Sabha or Rajya\nSabha - has decided to become paperless from the\nnext session",
    "answer": " Lok Sabha\n"
}{
    "question": "852)\uf020 The Department of Posts has decided to convert\nthe India Post Payments Bank into which type of\nbank",
    "answer": " Small Finance Bank\n"
}{
    "question": "853)\uf020 The Ministry of Statistics and Programme\nImplementation (MoSPI) started the 7th Economic\nCensus on July 29 from which state",
    "answer": " Tripura\n"
}{
    "question": "854)\uf020 The Economic Census is held after how many\nyears",
    "answer": " Five\n"
}{
    "question": "855)\uf020 The Global Tiger Day is celebrated on which date",
    "answer": "\nJuly 29\n"
}{
    "question": "856)\uf020 Which Indian state has largest number of tigers -\n526, as per the Tiger Estimation Report 2018",
    "answer": "\nMadhya Pradesh\n"
}{
    "question": "857)\uf020 One of the most challenging and prestigious\nsports event Tour de France is associated with\nwhich sports",
    "answer": " Cycle Race\n"
}{
    "question": "858)\uf020 Name the 22 years old Colombian who became\nthe youngest sportsman to win Tour de France in\nits 110 years history",
    "answer": " Egan Bernal\n"
}{
    "question": "859)\uf020 Name the Sr. IPS officer who has been appointed\nas the next Director General of Border Security\nForce-BSF",
    "answer": " V K Johri\n"
}{
    "question": "860)\uf020 Which state secured first position in the\ninstallation of rooftop solar projects with an\ninstalled capacity of 261.97 megawatts",
    "answer": " Gujarat\n"
}{
    "question": "861)\uf020 Which atomic power plant set a world record for\ncontinuous operation as its unit-1 functioned uninterrupted for 962 days",
    "answer": " Kaiga( Karnataka)\n"
}{
    "question": "862)\uf020 The first lot of four Boeing AH-64E Apache attack\nhelicopters was recently received from which\ncountry",
    "answer": " USA\n"
}{
    "question": "863)\uf020 The third edition of Khelo India Youth Games will\nbe held in______ in January, 2020",
    "answer": " Guwahati\n"
}{
    "question": "864)\uf020 Adhir Ranjan Chowdhury, the leader of the\nCongress party in Lok Sabha, was appointed as\nthe Chairman of the PAC. What is PAC",
    "answer": " Public\nAccounts Committee(of Parliament)\n"
}{
    "question": "865)\uf020 What is the function of PAC",
    "answer": " To review the\nreports of CAG- Comptroller and Auditor\nGeneral of India\n"
}{
    "question": "866)\uf020 _________ has become the first state to implement\nCentral government\u2019s proposal for introducing\n\u201cone-nation-one-card\u201d",
    "answer": " Telangana\n"
}{
    "question": "867)\uf020 What is the main purpose of the project \"One\nnation-one-card\"",
    "answer": " It aims for universal delivery\nof ration across the country through Aadhaar\nlinked Ration Cards"
}